Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we're going shopping today at EnglishPod.
我是Catherine，今天我们要在EnglishPod去购物。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are going to the store because we want to return a product.
今天我们要去商店，因为想退一件商品。
So maybe the product that we bought had some problem and we want our money back.
可能我们买的商品有问题，想把钱要回来。
That's right.
没错。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk more
那么我们来听一下今天的对话，稍后我们会回来继续讨论
about what's going on.
具体发生了什么。
Hi, I would like to return this TV.
你好，我想退这台电视。
Sure, do you have a receipt?
好的，您有收据吗？
Yeah, here you go.
有，给你。
Actually, I also want to return this keyboard.
其实，我还想退这个键盘。
Okay.
好的。
May I ask what the reason for returning these products is?
请问您退货的原因是什么？
The TV flickers a lot when I am watching a movie and at times the image is not very clear.
我看电影时电视闪烁得很厉害，有时画面不太清晰。
I see.
我明白了。
And what about the keyboard?
那键盘呢？
I spilled some coffee on it and now it won't work.
我洒了些咖啡在上面，现在它不能用了。
I'm sorry ma'am, but we can only exchange or refund defective products.
抱歉女士，我们只能换货或退款给有缺陷的产品。
We cannot take responsibility for misuse or damages.
我们不能为误用或损坏负责。
Fine.
好吧。
I don't know why they make these things so delicate anyways.
反正我也不知道他们为什么把这些东西做得这么脆弱。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some of those key words on Language Takeaway.
现在让我们看看“语言要点”中的一些关键词。
So we've got a great bunch of words for you here today.
今天我们为大家准备了一组很棒的词汇。
The first three are nouns and then afterwards we've got a couple of adjectives to describe
前三个是名词，之后我们有几个形容词来描述
those nouns.
这些名词。
But first up, we have the word receipt.
但首先，我们有“receipt”这个词。
That's right.
没错。
So we want to return the television and the worker there asks us if we have the receipt.
我们想退电视，店员问我们有没有收据。
Okay, a receipt is a small piece of paper that you receive from a clerk or a server
好的，收据是你从店员或服务员那里收到的一张纸，
after you buy something.
在你买东西之后。
So if I buy a TV, I will have this small piece of paper that says that I paid $500 for the
所以如果我买了一台电视，我会有一张纸，上面写着我为电视
TV.
付了500美元。
That's right.
没错。
So usually they will ask you for the receipt to see when you bought the product and if
所以他们通常会要你的收据，看看你什么时候买的商品，以及
you bought the product at that store.
你是否在那家店买的。
That's right.
没错。
So the receipt has all sorts of information, date, time, method of payment, cost, all those
所以收据上有各种信息：日期、时间、付款方式、价格，所有
things.
这些。
Right.
对。
And it's very important if you ever want to return something.
如果你想退货，它非常重要。
Now later on in the dialogue, the character explains why he wants to return the TV.
后来在对话中，角色解释了他为什么想退电视。
Now Marco, why does he want to do that?
那么Marco，他为什么想退呢？
Well, he has a problem with the TV when he's watching a movie.
嗯，他看电视电影时电视有问题。
Basically the image is not very clear.
基本上画面不太清晰。
So this is the keyword image.
所以这就是关键词“image”。
So image can mean a couple of different things.
“Image”可以指几种不同的东西。
You might hear the word image to mean a photograph or a picture like on a computer.
你可能听到“image”这个词指照片或图片，比如在电脑上。
But in this case, the image is how well you can see the images on TV, the things on TV.
但在这里，“image”是指你在电视上看到的画面质量，电视上的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So on TV, it's like you're seeing many, many images all at once or very rapidly together.
所以在电视上，就像你同时看到很多很多画面，或者快速连续地看到。
So maybe if you can't see clearly, you say that the image is not clear on the TV.
所以如果你看不清楚，你会说电视上的画面不清晰。
All right.
好的。
So if it's fuzzy, like there's gray and black, the image is not clear.
所以如果画面模糊，像有灰色和黑色，那画面就不清晰。
You can also say that, you know, I really like my new TV.
你也可以说，你知道，我真的很喜欢我的新电视。
The image is very clear.
画面非常清晰。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And not only are we returning a TV, but we're also returning a keyboard.
我们不仅退电视，还退一个键盘。
All right.
好的。
A keyboard, a key is something that you can push.
键盘，“key”是你按的东西。
But a keyboard is this thing that you use with your computer to type words.
但“keyboard”是你用来在电脑上打字的这个东西。
That's right.
没错。
So many of you who are using the website as we speak are using a keyboard and a mouse.
所以很多正在使用网站的朋友，现在就在用键盘和鼠标。
So these are probably one of the two most well-known objects when you're using a computer.
所以这些可能是使用电脑时最知名的两个物品之一。
That's right.
没错。
And keyboards come in many different shapes and sizes.
键盘有很多不同的形状和大小。
You can buy French keyboards and Russian keyboards.
你可以买法语键盘和俄语键盘。
So keyboard is the general word for this tool.
所以“keyboard”是这种工具的通用词。
Okay.
好的。
So we are returning the keyboard and the clerk explains that we can only return it if it
所以我们退键盘，店员解释说我们只能退如果它
is defective, if the product is defective.
有缺陷，如果产品有缺陷。
All right.
好的。
So this is one of those adjectives I talked about a minute ago.
所以这是我刚才提到的形容词之一。
Adjectives describe things.
形容词描述事物。
So my keyboard is defective or this TV is defective.
所以我的键盘有缺陷，或者这台电视有缺陷。
That means it doesn't work.
意思是它不能正常工作。
That's right.
没错。
So we have a defective product.
所以我们有一个有缺陷的产品。
It's not working properly.
它不能正常工作。
It has some problem.
它有些问题。
And well, the guy was complaining that he didn't understand why these things like the
嗯，那家伙在抱怨他不明白为什么这些东西，比如
keyboard are so delicate.
键盘，这么脆弱。
All right.
好的。
Delicate is something you might see written on the side of a box when you receive a package.
“脆弱”这个词你可能在收到包裹时在盒子侧面看到过。
Something that is delicate breaks very easily.
脆弱的东西很容易碎。
That's right.
没错。
So you have to handle with care.
所以你必须小心处理。
So for example, glass is very delicate.
比如，玻璃非常脆弱。
It can break easily.
它很容易碎。
All right.
好的。
Glass is delicate but stones, a big rock, that's not delicate.
玻璃是脆弱的，但石头，一块大石头，就不脆弱。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So that's all we have for language takeaway.
这就是我们语言要点部分的所有内容。
Let's review everything and listen to our dialogue.
让我们回顾一下所有内容，然后听我们的对话。
Hi.
你好。
I would like to return this TV.
我想退掉这台电视。
Sure.
当然。
Do you have a receipt?
你有收据吗？
Yeah.
有。
Here you go.
给你。
Actually, I also want to return this keyboard.
实际上，我还想退掉这个键盘。
Okay.
好的。
May I ask what the reason for returning these products is?
我能问一下退货的原因吗？
The TV flickers a lot when I'm watching a movie and at times the image is not very clear.
我看电影时电视经常闪烁，有时图像不太清晰。
I see.
我明白了。
And what about the keyboard?
那键盘呢？
I spilled some coffee on it and now it won't work.
我洒了些咖啡在上面，现在它不工作了。
I'm sorry, ma'am, but we can only exchange or refund defective products.
对不起，女士，我们只能换货或退款给有缺陷的产品。
We cannot take responsibility for misuse or damages.
我们不能为误用或损坏负责。
Fine.
好吧。
I don't know why they make these things so delicate anyways.
反正我不明白他们为什么把这些东西做得这么脆弱。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at a couple of phrases we've picked out for to be exact on Fluency
现在让我们看看我们在流利度构建部分挑选的几个短语，
Builder.
确切地说。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
The first verb we have today here in Fluency Builder is the main verb in today's dialogue,
今天我们流利度构建中的第一个动词是今天对话中的主要动词，
to return.
退货。
So I would like to return this TV.
所以我想退掉这台电视。
Okay.
好的。
So when you want to give back a product, you don't say I want to give back or anything
所以当你想退回一个产品时，你不会说“我想归还”或类似的话。
like this.
类似这样。
You say I want to return this product.
你会说“我想退掉这个产品”。
Well, it's not just giving back.
嗯，这不只是归还。
It's giving back and getting your money back.
这是归还并拿回你的钱。
That's right.
没错。
So to return means that you bring back the product and the store will give you back your
所以“退货”意味着你把产品带回来，商店会把钱退给你。
money.
没错。
That's right.
And he wanted to return the TV as we mentioned because the image was not very clear, but
他想退电视，就像我们提到的，因为图像不太清晰，但
he also mentioned that the TV flickers a lot.
他还提到电视经常闪烁。
So what is this to flicker?
那么什么是“闪烁”？
To flicker is another verb and flicker is something that things with light do.
“闪烁”是另一个动词，闪烁是带光的东西会做的事情。
The light flickers, the TV flickers.
灯光闪烁，电视闪烁。
It means the light comes on and off, on and off, on and off.
这意味着灯光一亮一灭，一亮一灭，一亮一灭。
So dark light, dark light.
所以暗亮，暗亮。
It's not very steady.
它不太稳定。
It's not like there's a light or dark.
它不是一直亮或一直暗。
And so this is very annoying when you're watching TV because it goes light, dark, light, dark
所以看电视时这很烦人，因为它一亮一暗，一亮一暗，
and it's hard to see what's happening.
很难看清发生了什么。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's basically just imagine someone is turning on and off the light all the time.
所以基本上就像想象有人一直在开关灯。
That's the same thing that's happening with the TV.
电视上发生的就是同样的事情。
It flickers.
它闪烁。
Exactly.
正是。
Or like when a light bulb in your lamp, when a light bulb is dying, it flickers.
或者像你台灯里的灯泡，当灯泡快坏时，它会闪烁。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So we wanted to actually return these goods and the clerk explained that we can exchange
所以我们实际上想退掉这些商品，店员解释说我们可以换货
or we can refund defective products.
或者退款给有缺陷的产品。
Okay.
好的。
These are two important verbs.
这是两个重要的动词。
Exchange means to trade one thing for another.
“换货”意味着用一件东西交换另一件。
So when I go to a foreign country, I exchange money, right?
所以当我去外国时，我换钱，对吧？
I can exchange Japanese yen for American dollars.
我可以把日元换成美元。
But at a store like an electronic store, I can exchange my TV that I don't like for maybe
但在像电子商店这样的店里，我可以把我讨厌的电视换成也许
a really good MP3 player or something like that.
一个很好的MP3播放器之类的东西。
So that's what happens usually if maybe your TV is broken or it had some problem, you exchange
所以通常如果你的电视坏了或出了什么问题，你会去换货。
it for a new one, right?
换一个新的，对吧？
But maybe you don't want the TV anymore.
但也许你不再想要那台电视了。
Maybe you changed your mind.
也许你改变了主意。
So you want to get a refund.
所以你想退款。
So refund, you hear this word fund, it has to do with money.
所以退款，你听到这个词里有“fund”，它和钱有关。
A refund means that the store will give you all your money back.
退款意味着商店会把你的钱全部退还。
So if I refund my TV, I give my TV to the store, the store gives me $500 or whatever
所以如果我退掉我的电视，我把电视还给商店，商店给我500美元或电视原来的价钱。
the money for the TV was, and I can buy anything else anywhere else.
然后我可以在任何地方买任何东西。
That's right.
没错。
So this is what happens when you get a refund, very different from exchanging the goods.
所以这就是退款的情况，和换货很不一样。
And finally, the clerk explained that they cannot take responsibility for misuse or damages.
最后，店员解释说他们不能对误用或损坏负责。
So remember this as a phrase.
所以记住这个短语。
This is really important to take responsibility.
这真的很重要：承担责任。
It means that if something goes wrong, you will take responsibility for it.
意思是如果出了问题，你会为此负责。
You will handle it.
你会处理它。
All right.
好的。
So for example, the store says that it can't take responsibility if something is broken.
比如，商店说如果东西坏了，他们不能承担责任。
That means that they won't pay you back money.
这意味着他们不会退钱给你。
That's right.
没错。
So if you buy a TV and you accidentally get it wet or you get water inside and this is
所以如果你买了一台电视，不小心把它弄湿了，或者水进去了，导致它损坏。
why it gets damaged, then the store cannot take responsibility for this damage.
那么商店不能为这个损坏承担责任。
Or you could say the other way around.
或者你也可以反过来用。
You could say, if you're at the office and you make a mistake on a report, you say, listen,
你可以说，如果你在办公室，在报告上犯了个错误，你说：“听着，老板，我真的很抱歉。”
boss, I'm really sorry.
我真的很抱歉。
I take full responsibility for this mistake.
我对这个错误负全责。
You can punish me or you can make me do it again.
你可以惩罚我，或者让我重做。
But I take responsibility means that I say it's my fault.
但“我承担责任”意味着我说这是我的错。
Right.
对。
You're guilty.
你有罪。
All right.
好的。
So that's all we have for Fluency Builder.
这就是我们“流利度构建”的全部内容。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we can review everything we've just learned.
让我们最后听一遍对话，回顾我们刚学的一切。
Hi, I would like to return this TV.
你好，我想退掉这台电视。
Sure.
好的。
Do you have a receipt?
你有收据吗？
Yeah.
有。
Here you go.
给你。
Actually, I also want to return this keyboard.
实际上，我还想退掉这个键盘。
OK.
好的。
May I ask what the reason for returning these products is?
我能问一下退货的原因吗？
The TV flickers a lot when I am watching a movie and at times the image is not very clear.
我看电影时电视经常闪烁，有时画面不太清晰。
I see.
我明白了。
And what about the keyboard?
那键盘呢？
I spilled some coffee on it and now it won't work.
我洒了些咖啡在上面，现在它不工作了。
I'm sorry, ma'am, but we can only exchange or refund defective products.
对不起，女士，我们只能换货或退款有缺陷的产品。
We cannot take responsibility for misuse or damages.
我们不能对误用或损坏负责。
Fine.
好吧。
I don't know why they make these things so delicate anyways.
反正我也不知道他们为什么把这些东西做得这么脆弱。
So returning goods is a very useful thing if you maybe bought a TV at a department store
所以退货是一件很有用的事，如果你可能在百货商店或电子商店买了电视。
or an electronic store, then you would want to return it if you had some problems.
那么如果出了问题，你会想退货。
Now, how easy or difficult is it to do?
现在，做这件事有多容易或多难？
Because in theory, in the dialogue, it seems like it's really easy.
因为理论上，在对话中，看起来很容易。
It depends on the store, of course.
当然，这取决于商店。
Some stores make it easier to do this.
有些商店让退货更容易。
Some stores make it harder.
有些商店让退货更难。
I can tell you in most stores, if you don't have a receipt, it's probably very difficult.
我可以告诉你，在大多数商店，如果你没有收据，可能非常困难。
Really?
真的吗？
Yes.
是的。
But a lot of stores have something else that they sell you or give you when you buy something.
但很多商店在你买东西时还会卖给你或给你别的东西。
It's called a warranty.
它叫保修。
And this is something that will help protect you if you take the TV home and you have a
这能保护你，如果你把电视带回家后出了问题。
problem.
出了问题。
Right.
对。
That means that they will come fix it or they will give you a new one without any questions
这意味着他们会来修好它，或者给你一个新的，不问任何问题。
about what happened.
不问发生了什么。
Now, not only can you return goods such as TVs, electronics or maybe clothes, but in
现在，你不仅可以退货像电视、电子产品或衣服这样的东西。
some cases also things that you buy at the supermarket, like maybe chicken.
在某些情况下，还有你在超市买的东西，比如鸡肉。
I've heard that maybe sometimes you buy chicken and you open it up that same day and it's
我听说过，有时你买鸡肉，当天打开它就坏了。
gone bad.
坏了。
Really?
真的吗？
I've never had that experience, but I think it makes sense.
我从未有过这种经历，但我觉得这说得通。
It depends where you buy it, of course.
当然，这取决于你在哪里买。
Right.
对。
Obviously at a supermarket and you show the receipt or maybe milk.
显然在超市，你出示收据，或者牛奶。
Maybe that's gone bad sometimes or yogurt.
也许有时牛奶或酸奶坏了。
Well, because they probably shouldn't sell it if it's bad.
嗯，因为它们可能不应该卖坏的东西。
Exactly.
完全正确。
If you tell them that they sold you bad milk, they'll give you a new one.
如果你告诉他们他们卖给你坏牛奶，他们会给你一个新的。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's called an exchange.
这就叫换货。
You would exchange the bad one for the good one.
你会把坏的那个换成好的那个。
Right.
对。
You wouldn't get your money back.
你不会拿回你的钱。
No.
不会。
Maybe, maybe not.
也许，也许不会。
Maybe.
也许吧。
All right.
好了。
So that's all the time we have for today, but this is actually a very interesting topic
今天的时间就到这里，但这其实是个很有趣的话题，
because it has to do a lot with customer service.
因为它跟客户服务有很大关系。
So let us know what your experience is with customer service, with returning something.
所以，告诉我们你在客户服务、退货方面的经历吧。
Is it very easy?
很容易吗？
Very difficult?
很难吗？
Actually some stores don't even accept returns.
实际上有些商店甚至不接受退货。
They say once you buy it, you cannot return it.
他们说一旦你买了，就不能退。
All sales final.
所有销售都是最终决定。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
So let us know.
所以告诉我们吧。
Are refunds or exchanges common where you come from?
在你那里，退款或换货常见吗？
And have you ever had a bad experience where you bought something and it didn't work when
你有没有过糟糕的经历，买了东西回家后
you got home?
发现它不能用？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Thanks again.
再次感谢。